Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
"But if you do
wrong, be afraid,
for he does not bear the sword
in vain.
He is the servant of God,
an avenger who carries out
God's wrath
on the wrongful."
I often thought of my friend,
Officer Reginald Dean Davis,
when I would read Romans 13:4.
That he punished two of the
three men who attacked him
before he himself was killed
means I will never think of
anyone else ever again
when I read or speak this verse.
He died protecting his family,
his friends and this city.
He was a servant of God.
I assuage my rage
that a third man escaped
by trying to remind myself
of a few things.
First,
Reginald found a woman
as strong, driven
and smart as he.
And then I think of his boy,
Andre,
and I see the same,
sometimes infuriating,
fearlessness,
inquisitiveness.
I know it may not
feel like it now,
but you got more from your
father, Andre, in 13 years
than most men will
in a lifetime.
He taught you to follow
your conscience,
to not take anyone else's word
about what is right and wrong,
to find a just code
in an often cruel world.
Thank you for making time
for IA at the end of your shift.
I didn't have a choice.
You could choose
not to be a cop.
Being a cop
isn't a choice for me.
What is it, then?
DNA.
At this point,
we don't need to spell out
why we're all here.
Yes, we do. Official procedure.
Any officer who discharges his
or her weapon in the line of duty
must justify
every round of ammunition.
You've shot
eight people in nine years.
Good shootings. Cleared on all.
Three since you
were made detective.
Four now.
The one who survived
was sentenced to life without.
Do you regret any?
I've been to the psychologist.
That's not an answer.
No, I do not regret any.
Faces don't come to you
in your sleep?
Justice comes at a cost.
Justice is not determined
by you.
But I am the sharp end
of that determination.
Says who?
My badge.
My oath.
Your DNA?
During the Civil War,
some soldiers just kept loading
their muskets without ever firing.
Five or six balls
loaded on top of each other.
In Vietnam, only 30% of frontline
infantry soldiers ever fired a shot.
So, ten soldiers in battle,
only three truly fighting.
Are you really using war analogies
here, Detective Davis?
What do you imagine
the other seven were doing?
Hi, Andre.
How's she doing?
Tired, but I just
gave her her meds.
All right, you can head home.
I got this.
Okay.
You know where to find me
if you need me.
What are we watching?
You left me.
No, Ma. I had to pull a triple.
I've been here too long.
I've...
I've overstayed my welcome.
Nah. You can never overstay
your welcome.
You're here to take me home.
This is home.
Don't leave me here, Reginald.
Ma...
it's Andre.
It's Dre, Mama.
I need to take my meds.
No, no, no. You took them.
You already took them.
You look tired.
You work too hard.
Yeah, you got that right.
It's the job.
It's what I do.
I know.
You gotta look the devil
in the eye.
Yeah.
Yeah, Ma.
Well, it looks just like
you said it would.
Hey, does yours smell
like your beard?
It smells like your girl.
Let's go.
Who the fuck are you guys?
We're the guys
that are taking your cocaine.
Not smart. You guys
are gonna fucking die.
Where is it?
Freezer. Downstairs.
We need a key?
Just two of you?
You're gonna be here all night.
Yo!
Move!
That's not 30 keys.
It's 300.
Somebody fucked up.
Shut up. On your knees.
Jeez.
This stuff hasn't been cut yet.
Jackpot! Fuck yeah!
No way. We walk.
-  What?
- We walk.
Small ain't always smart.
You can help or you can watch.
This is fucking stupid.
This is fucking freedom.
Shit.
Shh.
The fuck is this guy at?
He might be by the back door.
Check it out.
Car
back here is still running.
Back gate open.
Possible 30 in progress.
Shit. All right.
We're coming in.
Stay back.
Shots fired! Shots fired!
Officer down!
Cop! Run!
We don't want any more blood!
You don't have to kill him.
More are coming.
Drive.
Cover me.
Move the car.
8-5 Adam.
8-5 Charlie.
8-5 Charlie, on the air?
8-5 Frank?
Any units at Mosto's,
please advise.
Don't drive like an asshole.
Stop for this light.
- What the fuck are you doing? I said stop.
- We just fucking killed cops.
Fuck!
Central,
we got multiple officers down!
Put a rush on the bus.
I repeat, put a rush on the bus!
Central,
notify highways, blood banks.
Emergency Adam.
Main Central, show us en route.
Officers down.
Eight officers down.
Captain McKenna.
Okay, boys.
Detective Davis.
Captain McKenna runs the 8-5.
These are his boys
that died tonight.
My condolences.
Thank you.
It's Andre, right?
Yes, sir.
I never met your dad,
but I heard good things.
Thank you, sir.
Guys, I need you to get up.
You're sitting
in my crime scene.
Come on. He's got a job to do.
It's okay, Kelly.
I heard you were with IA today.
And I'd fucking love it if you
were right back there tomorrow.
If they give me cause.
Cause?
Here's your fucking cause
right there. Okay?
- You understand what I'm saying?
- Give me the room.
Your fucking cause times seven
lying dead in the fucking street.
Motherfuckers are giving you
all the reason you need...
Mac! You're not the only one
hurting here.
You're in public.
The public who never sees shit
when a cop goes down.
Lower your voice.
What were their names?
Uh, yeah.
Jennifer Montgomery
in the ambulance.
She's hanging on by a thread.
Massimo Adams, Charlie Cobb.
Jake Dominguez
and Danny Williams.
Out on the street
is Marcus Fernandez.
What?
Marcus Fernandez.
I knew Marcus.
We were at the academy together.
Out there with Marcus...
is Reuben Kizer
and Patrick Graham.
Just so you know,
they leave behind four wives,
one fiancée,
six kids.
Three are my godkids.
Now I'm gonna go wake them up
in the middle of the night,
let them know
their lives are shattered.
You know the drill.
Look, I fucking refuse
to allow these families
to be traumatized even more
with fucking trials and appeals
and horseshit narratives,
parole hearings for, fuck,
three, four decades.
I'm asking you...
to protect them from that.
I understand.
Why were they here?
My guys interrupted a robbery.
How much cocaine is this?
Crime Scene
estimates about 300 kilos
before the scumbags cut into it.
How much did they take?
About 50 keys.
One hundred and ten pounds.
That's A1 weight.
You're looking at 25 years.
Ninety-plus percent pure.
Two million, plus or minus,
before you step on it.
It's quadruple after.
Detective Andre Davis,
Detective Frankie Burns, DETF.
- She'll be working with you.
- With me doing what?
This is the biggest coke seizure
in I don't know how long.
- Narcotics will be involved.
- I appreciate the politics.
But if I don't catch these guys in the
next three or four hours, they vanish.
I don't do fucking politics.
And she's not the second team.
You can either fight me
or use me.
You good?
We should
fucking kill ourselves.
Don't be like that. Not now.
We just killed more cops
than I can fucking count, Ray.
I did all the killing.
You think they give a shit
about the body math?
They're gonna figure us out.
It was dark. We moved fast.
Car's not ours. Plates are stolen.
It'll get solved, Ray.
All right?
We both hate the fucking cops,
but they're smart.
They're gonna figure out our
names by sunrise. We need to run.
We need a plan. We need money.
Fuck!
Employee?
Yeah. Came up whistle-clean.
No-scroll good citizen
named Tom Cheaver.
So, Tom took his bullet
from just a few feet.
Notice the stippling
around the entrance wound.
And judging from
the proximity of that knife,
Tom tried to make a move.
Over here,
double taps.
Automatic weapon, suppressed.
I say two shooters.
Where are you seeing that?
No one's smooth enough
to murder all these officers
and hit Tom
coming up with a knife.
And one guy probably isn't carrying
100-plus pounds of cocaine out by himself.
Yeah, but it could be
more than two.
Nah. Look at
the shell groupings.
One was back there. He hit Tom.
The second one came this way.
Then he murdered all four of us.
Yeah.
Second one's a talented killer.
You left a zero off,
motherfucker.
What?
That wasn't 30 keys stepped on.
It was 300 pure.
Wasn't my fuckup.
Whose fuckup was it?
Hawk Tyler's, maybe?
He put the job out for bid.
But you guys
got something, right?
- Fifty keys.
- Well, good.
- Fuck you!
- I'm changing the deal.
You're not selling it for us
anymore.
You're gonna bring us to Hawk,
and we're gonna sell it ourselves.
And we're not splitting it
three ways.
I owe a lot of money
to a lot of people...
Me and Ray have to run for
the rest of our fucking lives!
Hawk ain't gonna hear
new deals.
Yeah, well, Hawk
hasn't heard 50 pure yet.
Give me your phone.
Hit.
We got a hit!
It's a red light cam.
Two men.
Alert everybody. Send it through
the mobile unit at Mosto's.
Detective Davis.
Sergeant Yolanda Bell,
shift supervisor at LMSI.
Good to know you, Yolanda Bell.
We got something for you.
How much you wanna bet when we find
that BMW, it's burnt to the chassis?
A nickel.
If you were gonna rob
660 pounds of coke,
would you drive a BMW two-door
to the job?
Would you bring
just one other guy with you?
Would you only take 50 keys?
No, no, and no.
They weren't expecting 300.
They weren't expecting cops,
either.
This was either dumb luck...
or a setup.
No, fuck you!
The FBI's here
because the shooters
are out of the state by now.
Half hour
since the final whistle.
Please, make one more
sports analogy.
If and when we get confirmation
that they crossed over
to Jersey or Connecticut...
The mayor would prefer that the
FBI take over sooner than later.
The mayor shits on us
every chance he gets.
The fucking guy
eats pizza with a fork.
He wants them
brought to justice.
No shit.
Dre.
Toine.
How'd it go
with Internal Affairs?
I'm here,
so not the way you hoped.
Like I said, the mayor
wants them brought to justice,
i.e., arrested, arraigned,
put on trial.
Not killed in a gun battle,
the details of which are foggy.
Like the seven behind us?
-  Who are you?
- Narcotics.
Beautiful. What could go wrong?
We got a narc and a trigger.
You better have perfect
diction, calling me a "trigger."
Cut the shit, everybody.
Has the mayor
got his thumb on this?
This an ask or an order?
They're still in New York.
You don't walk away
with 50 keys of 90% pure
unless you have
a big local buyer.
You don't move it far
unless you're into transport.
These guys were hitters,
not drivers.
You don't know that.
Good enough to kill seven cops,
dumb enough to run a red?
What they need to do
is sell the coke, vanish.
I'm not heading east.
Long Island runs out,
and it's all accountants
and dentists out that way,
so I'm a sore thumb.
I'm not going to Queens.
You don't wholesale coke
in the middle class.
I'm not staying in Brooklyn,
scene of the crime.
Plus, it's all pop-ups and
strollers and guys like you now.
Anyone left on Staten Island who can move
this kind of weight as quick as they need?
Not since the days before
Gotti murdered Castellano.
What about Jersey?
"Sopranos" was a TV show.
And upstate?
That's fucking ridiculous.
Ain't no way to move
50 keys of yayo in Utica.
Leaves Manhattan.
Detective Davis?
What, you got a hit for me?
911 call.
Black BMW, two-door,
on fire
in an alley in Chinatown.
Uh-oh, where's Chinatown?
- Manhattan.
-  Feel good?
- It does.
- How long ago was the 911?
-  Ninety seconds.
- Let's go.
- Wait, wait, wait.
- For what?
- Everything about these guys,
save the speed camera,
has been competent so far.
- Yeah, so?
- They'll sell the coke, catch a train,
catch a cab, jack a car,
and we're right back to hoping
we get a hit from a cam
before they vanish, show up
in Pennsylvania somewhere.
Good point.
Whereas the FBI is national...
Close the island.
What island?
Manhattan.
You having a seizure?
No, the mayor will buy it.
He's in the low 30s,
crime is ticking up,
homeless are pissing
in front of Tiffany's again,
and it's 1:00 a.m.,
not 1:00 p.m.
Anything goes wrong,
you can blame us.
Something will go wrong,
and then you're all fucked.
We get the concept of sacrifice is
like quantum physics to a fucking fed.
The mayor can say he was listening
to his commanders in the field.
Now, if your boss had a chance
to catch the murderers
of seven New York City cops
and chose not to, this city
would never forgive him.
Catch them by 5:00.
Wait, is that a yes or a no?
You all got balls,
not a lot of brains.
Good luck to you.
We'll be awaiting
your phone call.
Yeah, hold your breath.
How you gonna do this?
There are 21 bridges in and out
of Manhattan. Shut them down.
Three rivers, close them.
Four tunnels, block them.
Stop every train that leaves the island.
Amtrak, PATH, New Jersey Transit,
LIRR, Metro-North,
and loop the subways.
Then...
we flood the island with blue.
You wanna ditch a car,
you drive five blocks, not to Manhattan.
Two sets of tire tracks.
This was a meet-and-greet.
Miss Yolanda.
Hey, I need pictures of every car that
went into the alley after the BMW.
There aren't any cameras
aimed right at the entrances.
Alley backs up into massage
parlors and Chinese restaurants.
It's illegal workers. Every time a
camera goes up, it gets pulled back down.
Can you pick up every
passing vehicle on either end?
What interval?
From the time the BMW
went into the alley
to the first fire call to 911.
Will do. Stand by.
Are you who they say you are?
Who do they say I am?
You tell me.
You killed a lot of perps
in the last ten years.
Never shot first.
Never?
All right, let me be
more precise, Detective Burns.
I've never fired
without just cause.
Seven dead cops feels like
a lot of just cause.
These guys are killers.
So I need to know that we got
each other's backs tonight.
'Cause I got a kid at home.
Doesn't need to wake up
without her mother.
You wear that badge,
I got your back.
Talk to me.
All right.
-  Where we going?
- Uptown.
...has closed all
access into and out of Manhattan.
In a statement from city hall,
the mayor's office was only able to offer
a vague description
of the two suspects.
They tell us both are men.
One is white, one is black.
They are known to be armed
and extremely dangerous.
Deputy Mayor Antoine Mott defends
the decision to lock down the city.
His statement says, "With no way off
the island for these two fugitives,
the NYPD has every available...
- Nice.
- ...officer scouring Manhattan."
How much have you got?
Fifty kilos.
..."until this manhunt
is successfully completed."
- What up, B?
-  What up?
This ain't usual and customary.
Nothing is tonight, man.
This is Ray Jackson.
And this is Michael...
The bid you put out
was for 30 keys.
We walked in on 300.
Sometimes lightning strikes,
right?
And even better when you're
a borough away from it.
Yeah, most definitely.
Look, we killed cops,
and now we gotta run forever.
Then get on with your negotiations
and fuck your little guilt trip, word?
I'm a drug dealer
who hit a rival drug dealer,
and you're the guns
I got to do it.
You think I fucked you because
someone somewhere forgot a zero?
Our business doesn't attract a lot
of detail-oriented motherfuckers.
You don't like it,
make your own moves.
Or go drive an Uber.
Either way, let's make this deal
so I can get you America's
Most Wanted motherfuckers
out of my crib fast as I can.
One million.
Pesos?
Yo! I love it when fools strike gold
but don't know the market price.
Fifty keys cuts into 200.
Going rate for a cut key
in Manhattan is 32 G's.
That means
after a million to us,
that's still 5.4 million
for you.
He's one of those
detail-oriented motherfuckers.
Police!
Don't move! Search warrant!
To the left!
Police! Show me your hands!
Turn around!
Hey, come on.
What's going on?
Get off of him!
No, he didn't do anything!
He can't breathe!
You know if you kill him,
he can't tell us anything?
- Stand up. Step over here.
- Okay.
What's going on?
Is this you?
- No, that is not my car.
- It's registered in your name.
My ex-boyfriend, he had terrible
credit, so I put it in my name.
He said he sold it!
- He lied.
-  All the time.
You beat up the wrong man!
He'll live.
Get him out of here.
Let's go.
Hey. You okay?
Turn around.
Oh, God.
Knock it off. Knock it off.
It's all right. It's all right.
So, this ex-boyfriend
of yours...
Toriano Bush.
- What'd he do now?
-  Seven cops were murdered tonight.
-  Well, Toriano didn't do that.
- He picked up these two men.
We think they're the murderers.
There isn't a version of this
where these two aren't found.
Cooperate now.
Tell me something I don't know,
and that's the beginning of
the end of our time together.
Toriano couldn't
kill anyone, you know?
You said that.
But he's a criminal, right?
Small-time. Wanted to get out.
He was always just too deep in debt.
Is that why you left him?
Debt don't bother me.
Who was Becky
with the good hair?
This waitress ho at the Pan-Am.
- Check it.
- Thank you.
Sit.
Give us a sec.
Hey, Yolanda, get me everything
you have on Toriano Bush.
And get cameras up and around
the Pan-Am Lounge.
He has a girlfriend there.
Got it.
You have it in hundreds?
Brown people spend Benjamins,
brown people get followed.
Weighs as much as the coke.
You about right.
A million in 20s is 110 pounds.
And stay away from all canines.
They go Cujo because every dollar in
circulation is covered in cocaine atoms,
and y'all got 50,000 of those
bills in six small bags.
- How do I clean it?
- You don't know some dude who owns a strip club
- or a parking lot?
- This is seven figures.
Who do you use?
Who everybody else with
seven or more digits does.
Sudanese brother over in
the Meatpacking named Adi.
Cops, too. He's Switzerland.
What does that mean?
Means he's gonna take 300,000,
but he can sort bank accounts,
passports, whatever you need.
I heard about this dude.
Exclusive.
He owe you money?
Bush owes everybody money.
Yeah? How much?
$17,512, as of this morning.
What are you doing?
I just bought your Lincoln.
Let's get out of here.
They'll never know.
You'll never see me again.
I promise.
Yeah, that's...
probably Raymond Jackson.
"Probably"?
Because he always wears
a demon mask?
Not many white dudes born and raised
where we were during World War Crack.
Okay.
So he's a tough guy.
Yeah, fighting his whole life.
When we were kids,
I watched him beat a grown man
for stepping on this boy
Arvell's sneakers.
This was before the army.
Arvell?
Who's Arvell?
Arvell Trujillo.
He and Ray,
they joined up together.
They just did everything
together.
Is that who else is in the car?
No.
Arvell was blown up
in Afghanistan.
The other man in that car...
is probably Arvell's
little brother, Michael.
Because Ray protects him now.
Michael's smart, you know?
He could have been anything
if he'd have just been born
somewhere else.
But after Arvell was killed,
Michael joined up.
But I heard
he attacked a sergeant.
Okay.
Thank you.
- Come on in.
-  We are getting reports
of huge traffic jams at the outbound
entrances, bridges, and tunnels.
No one is getting off
this island tonight.
You're causing quite a stir.
...wanted for
the slaughter of seven officers
in Brooklyn tonight are Raymond
Jackson and Michael Trujillo.
Jackson, at 32 years old,
a long history of violent crime.
Trujillo, 26 years old,
also with an extensive rap sheet.
Both men are ex-military...
Put your bags in here.
Trujillo was
dishonorably discharged.
Fuck.
We're just getting a statement
from the NYPD, just issued.
We have been told that the injured
officer, Jennifer Montgomery,
was taken off life support and
declared dead just minutes ago.
Don't wanna count it?
No one cheats the man who
knows where all their money is.
Do not close that fucking safe.
What the fuck are you doing?
- I don't buy it.
- Buy what?
This guy, this place.
Where the fuck are we, Mike?
What are we doing?
This isn't us.
We have a million
in fucking cash.
You ever think we'd see that?
You ever think Arvell
even dreamed of this shit?
Now we're just gonna give it
to him? Then what?
He's gonna put it
in the fucking safe, type,
and give us
some fucking gift cards?
- It's that easy?
- Bush knew about this dude.
"Exclusive," remember?
Bush heard about him.
Fucking Toriano's
how all this started.
No, us not walking away
is how this started.
Look, Ray, I get it.
None of this shit makes any sense.
It ain't like anything
we've ever known.
But ain't no plan B I can see.
They shut down the island.
We can't run around with
100 pounds of stained cash.
He puts this money in some
accounts somewhere far from here,
and then we figure out
how to get to it later.
Ray, put it down.
You fuck us,
and I will fucking bury you
where you stand.
I need a fucking scotch.
I'll pour us both one.
We got a match.
We got a hit.
Bush is at the club.
Positive ID on Toriano Bush
at the Pan-Am.
Closest units,
converge on the Pan-Am Lounge.
Toriano Bush inside.
- Stay on the exits.
Nobody enters until I get there.
No, no! Listen to me, baby.
Police! Drop it!
- Bush!
-  Get the fuck back!
- Hey, get the fuck back!
- I'm an EMT.
I don't give a shit!
Get the fuck back!
Out of the way.
Get out of the way!
Watch it, watch it, watch it.
Move, move, move!
Come on, Andre.
Answer your fucking phone.
What the fuck is this?
Hey!
- Didn't I say wait?
-  We disobeyed.
- You disobeyed?
- He didn't kill one of your brothers.
So fuck if I'm gonna
let him get away with...
What are you, fucking stupid?
He didn't kill anybody!
He could have led us
to the two who did!
We yelled.
He pulled. We shot.
End of story.
One down, two to go.
That's fucking bullshit!
Says the side piece
of a man who helped
fucking cop killers!
How many drinks
you have tonight?
Hey, don't do
what you're doing right now.
Get your fucking hands off me.
No!
What? What?
Officer,
get them the fuck out of here. Let's go.
You said Bush pulled.
Pulled what?
A fucking .38?
The other two got suppressed
submachine guns,
and Bush was carrying a piece you only
ever see in a meth addict's glove box...
or a fat cop's ankle holster.
Hey, whoa, whoa.
Who was that, LMSI?
Nanny. Sorry.
My little girl's...
Is everything all right?
No, but we'll be fine.
What the fuck is going on here?
That's what I'm trying
to figure out.
Bahamas is right
for your skin color.
You'll go via Miami.
Three hundred twenty-six
is short.
The rest is cash.
You are now Christopher James.
And, Ray, your new name
is William Simpson.
Take separate buses to Miami.
There's a man named Swift
in Little Havana.
He runs a bar at the corner
of Flagler and 27th Street.
He also sells passports.
They'll be under your new names.
Then you will pay cash
for a charter boat to Nassau.
There is a ski boot bag
and backpack behind that door.
I'll put 15 in each...
What was that?
It's exactly
what it sounds like.
Whoever is at my door,
you wait and you think.
NYPD! Open up!
What precinct are you from?
Because I'll have your fucking...
Going in!
Fuck!
You two
better not have fucked up.
Are we good?
Is this my case, Captain?
This is all hands on deck,
but you're lead.
Someone should tell them.
Look, they're angry.
They're in pain.
Butchco and his wife were
close with Jennifer Montgomery.
She didn't make it.
They just pulled the plug.
10-13, we need backup!
This is Kelly!
We're on Ninth and 13th,
shots fired! 10-13!
Ninth and 13th! Suspects
Trujillo and Jackson here!
How the fuck
did Kelly find them?
I can't see anything.
I can't fucking see.
We didn't fuck you over, man.
I swear.
Put those guns in your
mouths, you motherfuckers!
Fucking 8-5.
What?
Throw your guns down,
you motherfuckers!
It's his thumb drives.
The thumb drives!
What is it?
- "Coolhand."
- Huh?
"Coolhand," one word, lowercase.
Get the shotgun.
Get the shotgun!
We gotta fucking move.
All units,
suspects are 90Z on foot!
- Right there. Don't call it in.
- Vicinity of Ninth and 13th.
They're ours.
We gotta split up.
We're too easy to track
if we're together.
No. No way, man. You need help.
Head down, eyes up.
I'll see you in Miami.
Go!
Okay.
He ain't like me.
Mike.
Is Ray dead?
I hope so.
Michael?
Is he dead?
Yes.
Stop walking.
You got a clear shot. Take it.
Don't worry about me.
You got lucky.
Yeah.
Luckier than the civilian
he just murdered.
Add that to the list of cops.
How many bodies stacked up
against you now that Ray is dead?
- Don't try and get into my head, okay?
- Simple truths, Michael.
And don't use my name!
Take the shot!
Stop fucking walking!
I think most of this mess
is his.
But you're balls-deep
in it now, Michael.
For guys like Ray,
I'm natural causes.
But what about you?
Fuck you know
about guys like Ray, huh?
about guys like me?
Saw your records.
Marine. Tried to follow in your brother's
footsteps after he got sent home in a box.
But you...
dishonorably discharged.
Insubordination.
I get it.
Some of us are killers, Michael.
But you, I think the last thing you
want is to take a life for no reason.
And how you know that, huh?
Because you would have
killed her by now.
Shoot him!
-  No!
- Fucking shoot him!
Michael wants to talk.
So, come on, Michael.
Let's talk.
He wants to talk, tell him to do it
without a gun to my fucking head, Andre.
Burns, be cool.
This is fucking cool.
Just give me a second here.
None of this shit
makes any sense.
The manager at the spot we hit,
he knew the cops were coming.
It's called a silent alarm.
No. He checked his watch
before it all happened.
And the first four
came peacefully.
I mean, one fucking knocked with his
knuckles like a Jehovah's Witness,
not with the side of his hand
like a fucking cop.
Andre, for the love of Christ,
are you really gonna entertain this shit?
Three hundred keys, pure.
I mean, what the fuck?
This whole thing is filthy.
You can't move that type of weight
around without cartels or cops or both.
And the cops shot
the Cleaner upstairs,
fired right through
the peephole, no warning.
They were there
for more than just us.
And right before we left,
the Cleaner gave me thumb drives.
Gave what?
Drives.
USBs and shit.
- What's on them?
-  Andre.
All he said was "8-5."
Cop-killing piece of shit!
- There's no fucking...
- Burns, stop! Stop!
Michael, look at me.
- Don't fuck with me!
-  Nobody's fucking with you.
But facts: You shoot her,
I'm gonna kill you in the same breath.
And everything you think you
know or may have means nothing.
So drop your weapon,
and let's take a look at the drives.
No. No, I can't do that.
- Michael, I need you to trust me.
- I don't trust anybody!
You have no choice.
You're not gonna escape to some island
somewhere, even after they open this one.
You're smart enough
to know that.
I am, huh?
The world's just gonna
keep closing in on you.
But you can survive this if you
just give yourself up to me.
No! Michael!
No!
Are you okay?
What the fuck are you doing?
- This is Davis.
Lock down everything
in a seven-block radius
from Weichsel Beef's
center of the circle.
Positive ID on Michael Trujillo
leaving there 90 seconds ago.
Trujillo has information
vital to this case.
He must be brought in alive.
- Let me see.
- I'm fine.
Yeah, you look it.
I wanna know
what's on those drives.
Central, advise the
units that are 84 to set up a perimeter
from West 12th Street to West 19th
and from Eighth Avenue to the water.
No one in or out.
What? Can you believe that?
Disgusting. It's disgusting.
And the pool
is on the 26th floor.
-  Shh!
I won't hurt you
if you stay quiet.
You got it?
Nod.
Shit. Fuck.
What's the password?
Um...
"Eightclap1."
Gotta spell the word "eight."
One is the number.
- One word?
- Mm-hmm.
Close your eyes.
Why didn't you shoot him?
They told me you were fearless.
The guy who kills cop killers.
I just need the truth,
that's all.
You believe a cop killer?
Good work, Kelly. Get some rest.
You took down
one vicious son of a bitch.
Yeah, not before he killed
an innocent civilian.
World's a better place
with that guy gone.
You seen his record?
Glanced at it.
I knew I had the right guy
for this.
All hands on deck, right?
It was your boys who smoked
them out of this apartment.
How did Lieutenant Kelly
even get here so quick?
Look at this fucking mess.
- You still got one guy on the run, right?
- Yeah.
It's 4:37 a.m.
You've got less than an hour
before I gotta open the island.
You haven't gotten him by then,
we're all eating shit for breakfast.
Don't worry about
the other perp.
Andre put that motherfucker
in a seven-block box.
He's on borrowed time.
Michael
Trujillo is still at large,
but police believe he is surrounded
somewhere inside the Meatpacking District.
The mayor's office
has praised NYPD officers
for the progress
they've made in this manhunt.
Deputy Mayor Antoine Mott
had this to say
in a press briefing
just moments ago.
Mayor Drum cut
short his trade mission to the EU
and is already on a plane home
from Brussels.
Asked me to pass along his gratitude
to the citizens of this city.
"World's greatest," his words.
Without your patience
and assistance,
and, I'll add, the boldness
of Mayor Drum's idea
to close Manhattan
in the first place,
we wouldn't have already neutralized
two of the three men responsible
for the ambush at Mosto's
that claimed the lives
of eight of our finest
from the 85th Precinct
last night.
A gunman identified as
Raymond Jackson
and his accomplice,
Toriano Bush,
both died resisting arrest in
the early hours of this morning.
Both men were armed
and dangerous.
Our brave officers
at the 85th Precinct...
Eighty-fifth.
"Eight-five."
We believe
we have the third man,
Michael Trujillo,
within our grasp.
Eighty-five.
We ask all residents
to shelter in place
while we apprehend Trujillo and
hold him accountable for his crimes.
Badge numbers.
Every number's a cop.
Help! Help! Help!
Could I speak to the
director of security, please?
I'm sorry, Officer,
just one moment.
Reception.
What?
Sir, you can't be back here.
Where are we going?
We gotta bring him in alive.
...assault at the
Parallax Hotel. Sounds like Trujillo.
Direction of flight was
through the kitchen at rear.
That's 13th Street. Lock him in.
Nobody approach him! He's mine!
Sir, stop.
Hold it right there!
Show me your hands!
Take the car!
Cut him off on the other side!
Don't shoot!
-  Trujillo! Drop your weapon!
Police.
Stop, drop on the ground.
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Police.
Police, don't move,
don't move, don't move.
Clear the doorway.
NYPD. Take cover.
Clear! Clear!
Come on, clear!
Police. Clear, clear.
Out of the way. NYPD.
Take cover.
Move. Move. Move.
Clear. Clear. Clear.
Drop it!
You're the only cop tonight who
speaks first and shoots second.
It's fucking morning,
and you killed eight of us.
Not all eight were clean.
Who cares?
You do.
How do you know
I'm any different?
Because you would have
shot me by now.
Where are those drives
we were talking about?
I stashed them.
Okay.
Give them to me,
and I'll keep you alive.
No.
You want the drives,
you let me go.
If you don't walk out with me,
you'll be carried out by others.
Michael, your only hope
is to tell the truth,
pray to God for forgiveness,
and make peace with the fact
that you may die in prison.
Shooting you sounds
a whole lot better right now.
You don't want my face
and this dirty subway
to be the last things
you ever see.
If I die, you'll never find
out what's on those drives.
I may not find the drives,
but I will find out
why tonight happened.
But could you prove it?
I only have to prove it
to myself.
Come on, Michael.
Come on.
Okay.
Cease fire!
What the fuck?
What the fuck, man?
He was surrendering.
He was giving himself up.
He was gonna shoot you.
You didn't see the gun down?
You didn't fucking see
the gun down?
I thought he was gonna shoot.
Central, this is homicide 4-3.
Do you copy?
Central, do you copy?
Be advised, we have shots
fired on the 6 train
coming into Grand Central.
Suspect is down.
"Coolhand."
Do you copy?
Central?
"Coolhand."
Central, do you copy?
Central?
Central, advise if you receive
my transmission.
Shit.
Is he gone?
What do you think?
I think they called
the right man for the job.
Hey. Good job.
You did great work.
Way to go. Well done.
Congratulations, Detective.
Thank you, sir.
- Amazing.
- Thanks, guys.
Hey.
What's up?
- This fucking thing is dead.
-  Oh.
Can I borrow yours?
Yeah, of course.
- I'll bring it right back.
- Sure.
Good work, Detective.
Great job, Burns.
Thanks, Kelly.
- How's the hand?
- Okay.
Okay. Yes, ma'am.
Voice mail.
Shit.
It's been a long night.
You get some rest.
Yeah, you too.
Go hug that daughter of yours.
Manhattan
reopened at 7:05 this morning
after a night of carnage that
saw eight police officers...
...into and out of
Manhattan were closed last night.
...personally oversee the
successful conclusion of the manhunt...
...flooded by the NYPD
in what looked and felt like
a military invasion.
What's up?
Goddammit.
Okay, all right, calm down.
Just come over to my place.
Yeah.
I understand.
We'll figure something out.
Just...
I gotta go.
I got a visitor.
Put your gun down here.
Who was on the phone?
My wife.
She's a nurse.
Shift just started.
And that's the story
of all married life.
Guy that owned Mosto's
was your partner.
Mosto's was your vault.
The 8-5 was armored security, moving
drugs around the city in NYPD vehicles.
Last night was just fucking
bad luck on every level.
A rival hits Mosto's at the same time
your boys drop by to move a load of coke,
run into men
with training, die, badly.
Those men with training escape,
sell the drugs and clean the money,
coincidentally with
the same launderer you use.
And you scorch earth
trying to cover it all up.
You're really good.
Not good enough.
Not all the cops killed
last night were a part of it.
Clean or dirty,
they're all dead 'cause of you.
So you know,
this is not about Cadillacs and
fucking Rolexes, material bullshit.
Not for me.
Not for most of my guys.
It's about having a life.
My first month running the 8-5,
I went to two of my cops' funerals.
First one went 60 miles an
hour into a bridge abutment.
His blood alcohol was .25.
Second guy
drank himself to death too.
Cirrhosis.
Three of my cops
had their homes foreclosed on.
Another guy lost his apartment.
Shitty landlord
doubled the rent.
The divorce rate in the 8-5
was over 70%.
This is about my cops
staying married,
raising their kids,
not having to spend four hours
a day sitting in traffic,
crawling to and from a city
they can't afford to live in,
a city that actively
fucking dislikes them.
But a city that they protect...
with their lives
every fucking day.
That's what this is about.
I'll tell you what, anybody tells you
money can't buy happiness is full of shit.
And the 8-5 is proof.
Frankie Burns is proof.
Did you put her on this just to
make sure I did your bidding?
I put her on this 'cause she
might be as good as you.
And she's got everything
to lose.
Three guys murdered my father.
He took two with him.
But the third,
he hit my dad so many times he
broke every bone in his face.
That's why we had to have
a closed casket.
Guy told the judge...
he didn't even remember
doing it.
He was so jacked, so...
so high on cocaine
and angel dust.
The drugs
have always been there.
And they always will be.
And people will always die
because of them.
That blood, that blood
cannot be on the badge.
You can't prove where
those flash drives came from.
And nobody is gonna
take the stand against me.
So if you go down this road,
Andre, you're on your own.
You'll be looking over your
shoulder the rest of your life.
- I know.
Or you could just look
the other way.
I'd rather
look the devil in the eye.
I get you?
You wouldn't ask
if you didn't know.
Hurts like a motherfucker,
right?
I'll live.
You can if you give yourself up.
It's the only choice
available to you right now.
Maybe.
Don't do it.
He's gone.
It's over.
So put your gun down.
I'm gonna turn around
and face you, Burns.
No.
I'm gonna turn around.
I have the drives.
I copied them.
They're already
out in the world.
You're going down, Burns.
Every dirty cop in the 8-5
is going down.
You pull that trigger,
you get life.
Your daughter doesn't need to
grow up without her mother.
Badge too.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org